Finding Aid for Michigan Sea Grant Program records
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Research Project Files
  - Education
    - Great Lakes Limnology Course Project Report (E/CCD-2) 1979-1980 (Box 10)
    - Development and Emplacement of University Level Education Programs for the Production of Work Boats (E/CCD-4) 1982-1983 (Box 10)
    - Underwater Technology Education (E/CCD-5) 1978, 1982-1983, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Ship Building Short Course (E/GLD-4) 1980-1983, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Recreation Scuba Diving Population/Safety Survey and Public Education for Michigan (E/DS-2) 1975 (Box 10)
    - Underwater Education Workshop Program (E/DS-4) 1976-1980 (Box 10)
    - Scientific/Academic Diver Education Series (E/DS-5) 1980 (Box 10)
    - Expanded Food and Nutrition Education Program Involvement in the Sea Grant Program (A/FP-1) 1978-1979 (Box 11)
  - Fisheries (Great Lakes Fisheries)
    - Subprogram information (Box 11)
    - Applicability of Purse Seines to Harvest Fish from the Upper Great Lakes (R/CF-1) 1976 (Box 11)
    - Evaluation of Small Mesh Trap Nets for the Harvest of Round Whitefish (Prosopium Cylandraceum), and Underutilized Species (R/CF-3) 1977-1980 (Box 11)
    - Improved Fish Handling, Packaging and Processing (R/CF-4) 1977-1979 (Box 11)
    - Biology and Commercial Potential of Underutilized Fish: Carp (R/CF-4) 1978 (Box 11)
    - Market Development Prospects for Michigan Fisheries (Determinants of Fishing Effort) (R/CF-5) 1979 (Box 11)
    - Developing a Model Commercial Fisheries Statute For the Great Lakes States (R/CF-7) 1979 (Box 11)
    - Economic Value of Michigan Commercial Fishery through Carp (R/CF-8) 1979-1981 (Box 11)
    - Improved Fish Handling, Packaging, and Processing Methods (R/FP-1) 1977-1979 (Box 11)
    - Incidence and the Types of Stress Induced Diseases in Selected Fishes in the Great Lakes (R/FPA-1) 1980-1981 (Box 11)
    - The Development of a Comprehensive Atlas of Lake Michigan, Planning Study (R/GLF-1) (Box 11)
    - PCB's, DDT Compounds and Dieldrin Levels in Carp (R/GLF-2) 1979-1981 (Box 11)
    - Identification of Current Spawning Grounds and Prediction of Potential Spawning Areas for Yellow Perch in South East lake Michigan, with Estimate of Associated Early Growth, Survival and Recruitment (R/GLF-4) 1981 (Box 11)
    - Compensatory Response of Lake Trout and Lake Whitefish to Exploitation (R/GLF-5) 1979 (Box 11)
    - Competition Between Juvenile Salmon and Trout in Great Lakes Spawning Streams (R/GLF-6) 1980 (Box 11)
    - Renewed Use of Underutilized Species of Great Lakes Fish for Animal Feed (R/GLF-7) 1979-1981 (Box 11)
    - Evaluation of Modified Large-Mesh Trap Nets for the Harvest of Lake Whitefish in an Area of Strong Current and Rocky Bottom. (GLF-10) 1980 (Box 11)
    - Examination of Spawning and Incubation Requirements, and Reproductive Biology of Lake Trout in Relation to re-establishment of self-sustaining Stocks in the Great Lakes (R/GLF-11) 1982 (Box 11)
    - Age, Length Composition, and Catch per Effort of Lake Whitefish in Trap Nets from Indian Treaty Waters of Whitefish Bay, Lake Superior (R/GLF-12) 1980-1981, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Evaluation of an Artificial Reef as a Fishery Management Method for Lake Michigan (R/GLF-13) 1981 (Box 11)
    - Development of a Management Model for Lake Superior Lake Herring Stocks (R/GLF-14) 1980-1987, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Population Dynamics and Yield Potential of Lake Superior Pink Salmon (Oncorhynchus gorbuscha) (R/GLF-15) 1981-1987 (Box 11)
    - Whitefish Stocks in Northern Lake Michigan (R/GLF-16) 1980-1984 (Box 11)
    - Movement, Growth and Mortality of Yellow Perch in Saginaw Bay (R/GLF-17) 1984 (Box 11)
    - Feeding Behavior, Distribution, and Diet of Salmonids in Lake Huron (R/GLF-18) 1985 (Box 11)
    - Whitefish Stocks in Northern Lake Michigan (R/GLF-19) 1985-1989 (Box 11)
    - Relative Contribution of Inland Spawned Fish to the Lake Michigan Yellow Perch Stock (R/GLF-22) 1986-1988 (Box 11)
    - Effects of Hypertoxic Environment on the Survivability of Hatchery raised Rainbow Trout (Salmo gairdneri, kamloops) (R/GLF-27) 1987-1989 (Box 11)
    - Competition for Food Among the Major Predators in Saginaw Bay (R/GLF-29) 1987-1990 (Box 11)
    - Distinguishing between Naturally Produced and Stocked Walleyes in Traverse Bay (R/GLF-3) 1989-1991 (Box 11)
    - Comparative Analysis of Year Class Strength and Population Parameters of Pink Salmon in the Upper Great Lakes (R/GLF-32) 1989-1991 (Box 11)
    - Year Class Strength of Rainbow Smelt and Lake Whitefish as Influenced by Interspecific Interaction and Climate (R/GLF-35) 1989-1991 (Box 11)
    - Alewife Survival Rates and Recruitment Under Low Population Levels in Lake Michigan (R/GLF-36) 1990-1993 (Box 11)
    - Influence of Compensatory Mechanisms in Lake Trout Dynamics (R/GLF-37) 1987-1989 (Box 11)
  - Program Development (Program Development Funds)
    - History of Grand Traverse Bay, (No ID number) 1970s (Box 11)
    - Feasibility Study of Modeling Certain Water Quality Aspects of the Great Lakes (No ID number) 1969-1970 (Box 11)
    - Meteorological Study of Power Plant Thermal Discharges (No ID number) 1973 (Box 11)
    - Biological Productivity Models Projects 1970-1971 (Box 11)
    - A Manual of Limnological Methods (No ID number) 1982 (Box 12)
    - The Role of the Great Lakes in Michigan's Economic Future: A Conceptual Framework 1983 (Box 12)
    - Great Lakes Ice Research Workshop at Ohio State University 1983 (Box 12)
    - Commercial Fishing in the Great Lakes 1983 (Box 12)
    - Conference on Shipping Nationals/UNCATD Liner Code/Bilateralism 1983 (Box 12)
    - Divers for Placement of Lake Trout Egg Baskets in Various Habitats 1986, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - PCB Residues in Lake Michigan Salmonids Collected from the Ludington Area: Variations Due to Species, Size and Season (M/PM-3E) 1989 (Box 12)
    - Sawdust and Wood Chip Deposits in Near-Shore Lake Michigan Waters Near Manistique, Michigan (M/PM-1) 1980 (Box 12)
    - Program Development Misc. (M/PM-3) 1986 (Box 12)
    - Michigan Maritime Museum (M/PM-3) 1987-1990 (Box 12)
    - Ocean Erosion Laboratory (M/PM-3) 1987 (Box 12)
    - Great Lakes Coastal Dune Management Research, (M-PM-3) 1987 (Box 12)
    - Support and Analysis and Publication of Lake Erie Fish Larvae Dataset (M/MP-3) 1983 (Box 12)
    - Analysis of Lake Trout Eggs for Toxic Substances (M/MP-3) 1986 (Box 12)
    - Evaluation of Double-Crested Cormorant Deterrents in Lake Superior Pound Nets (M/MP-3) 1983 (Box 12)
    - Development and Publication of Fish Bibliography (M/MP-3) 1987, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Assessment Survey for Guidance of Continuing Education Courses Regarding Great Lakes Resources (M/MP-3) 1986 (Box 12)
    - Saginaw Bay Resource Planning and Management Symposium (M/PM-3) 1986-1987 (Box 12)
    - Plastic Debris Literature Search (M/PM-3) 1987-1988 (Box 12)
    - Assessing Consequences of Nutrient Enrichment in Lake Erie with Sediment Bioassay (M/MP-3) 1983 (Box 12)
    - Great Lakes Coastal Dunes Management (M/MP-3) 1987 (Box 12)
    - Working Level Workshop if Great Lakes Coastal Processes/Coastal Erosion Research Needs (M-PM-3C) 1987 (Box 12)
    - Extra Funds for K. Huggins to finish publications (M/MP-3) 1987-1988 (Box 12)
    - Commercial Fishing in the Great Lakes (M/MP-3) 1983 (Box 12)
    - Natural Recruitment of Chinook Salmon from the Pere Marquette River (M/PM-3F) 1988-1989 (Box 12)
    - Investigation of Zebra Mussel Impact of the Great Lakes Marine Interests (M/PM-3J) 1990-1991 (Box 12)
    - Literature Assessment on Great Lakes and Human Health (M/PM-3K) 1992 (Box 12)
    - Literature Appraisal on Human Reproduction and Development (M/PM-3L) 1992 (Box 12)
    - Biological Control of Zebra Mussels (Dreissena polymorpha) by Redear Sunfish (Lepomis microlophus) (M/PM-3M) 1992 (Box 12)
    - An Evaluation of Science Education as a Mean of Improving Great Lakes Citizens Skills for Decision Making Under Risk. (M/PM-30) 1993 (Box 12)
  - Recreation and Tourism
    - Subprogram information (Box 12)
    - Resource Land Use Capabilities and Recreation Behavior Patterns (R/R-1) 1969-1972 (Box 12)
    - Michigan Great Lakes Recreational Boating-Demand, Supply, Marketing, Economic Impact (R/R-2) 1982 (Box 12)
    - Regional variations in the market; Potential for Great Lakes Boating (R/R-3) 1981 (Box 12)
    - The Perceived Influence of Fuel Price and Availability Upon Great Lakes Boating Behavior Among Urban Michigan Boaters (R/R-4) 1981 (Box 12)
    - Economic Impact of Angling for Great Lakes Fish in Michigan, (R/R-5) 1983 (Box 12)
    - Information Networks and Great Lakes Implications for Increasing Tourism in Michigan (R/R-6) 1983 (Box 12)
    - Images and Perceptions of the Great Lakes (R/R-7) 1983 (Box 12)
    - Tourism market Segmentation (R/R-8) 1983 (Box 12)
    - Information Networks in the Great Lakes Tourist Industry: Implications for Tourism in Michigan (R/R-13) 1984 (Box 12)
    - Segmenting Michigan's Sport Fishing Market (R/R-14) 1984 (Box 12)
    - Attitude Image and Perception Shifts Following Great Lakes Vacation Travel (R/R-15) 1986-1988 (Box 12)
    - Community Integration into Great Lakes Tourism Information Networks (R/R-17) 1985-1986 (Box 12)
    - Influence and Exchange Networks in Among Tourism Oriented Businesses in of Four Michigan Communities (R/R-17) 1988 (Box 13)
    - Information-Seeking Behavior by Travelers to Michigan's Great Lakes (R/R-17) 1987 (Box 13)
    - Segmenting and Developing Demand Equations MI's Sport Fishing Market (R/R-19) 1985 (Box 13)
    - Recreation and Tourism Forecasting (R/CE-1) 1990 (Box 13)
  - Saginaw Bay Research
    - Saginaw Bay Research Institute (R/SB-1) 1980-1992 (Box 13)
    - AT 800 Very Large Interlake Bulk Carrier Feasibility Study 1969-1971 (Box 13)
  - Transportation
    - Miscellaneous Project Reports 1978-1980 (Box 13)
    - Michigan State Transportation Report and Notes 1981 (Box 13)
    - Shoreline Effects of the Vessel Transit of the St. Mary River (R/T-6) 1979 (Box 13)
    - Ice Strengthening of Great Lakes Bulk Carriers (R/T-9) 1980-1982, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - A Study of the Feasibility of Moving Western Coal Through a Transshipment Point Located on Lake Michigan (R/T-11) 1980 (Box 13)
    - Multivariable Control of Diesel Controllable Pitch Propellers Propulsion Systems (R/T-15) 1983 (Box 13)
    - An Investigation of Low Speed Energy Experiments Conducted in Traditional Towing Tanks (R/T-16) 1983-1984 (Box 13)
    - Finite Element Systems Analysis of Elastohydrodynamic Stern Bearings (R/T-17) 1984 (Box 13)
    - Use of Multiple Graphics Work Stations in Interactive Hull Generation (R/T-18) 1984, 3 folders (Box 13)
    - Reliability Analysis of Marine Diesel Propulsion Systems Toward Rational Maintenance, Repair, and Replacement Decisions (R/T-19) 1987-1989, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Time Varying Behavior of Elastohydrodynamic Stern Bearings (R/T-21) 1985-1987 (Box 13)
    - The University of Michigan/Sea Grant/Industry Consortium in Offshore Engineering (R/T-23) 1987-1989 (Box 13)
    - The University of Michigan/Sea Grant/Industry Consortium in Offshore Engineering (R/T-25) 1987-1989 (Box 14)
    - Developing an Improved Model for Predicting the Resistance of planning Boats (R/T-26) 1989-1991 (Box 14)
    - Sea-keeping and Dynamic Stability of High-Speed Planing Craft (R/T-27) 1989-1991 (Box 14)
    - Predicting Complicated Dynamics Leading to Vessel Capsizing (R/T-28) 1989-1990 (Box 14)
    - The University of Michigan/Sea Grant/Industry Consortium in Offshore Engineering (R/T-29) 1987-1989 (Box 14)
    - Continuing Developing an Improved Model for Predicting the Resistance of Planning Boats (R/T-30) 1991-1993 (Box 14)
    - A Nonlinear Probalistic Approach to Fishing Vessel Capsizing (T/T-32) 1991-1993 (Box 14)
  - Toxic Substances
    - Subprogram and miscellaneous information (Box 14)
    - Trace Element and Nutrient Input to Saginaw Bay from Pollution Aerosol (R/EP-5) 1974 (Box 14)
    - The Effects of Polychlorinated Biphenyls, A pollutant of Great Lakes Fish on the Embryotoxicity of Mink (R/TS-1 and R/TS-2) 1977 (Box 14)
    - Absorption of Polychlorinated Biphenyls on Suspended Solids and Their Distribution and Differential; Accumulation in Rivers, Harbors, and Lake Systems (R/TS-3) 1977 (Box 14)
    - The Role of Sediments and Suspended Particulate Material in the Translocation of PCB's in Aquatic Environments (R/TS-4) 1977-1979 (Box 14)
    - The Bioaccumulation of PCB's by Food Web Concentration in Fish (T/TS-5) 1977-1979 (Box 14)
    - Uptake, Accumulation and Removal of Polychlorinated Hydrocarbons (PCB's) by Great Lakes Phytoplankton and Zooplankton, (T/TS-6)1978-1981 (Box 14)
    - Change in PCB Concentration for Commercial and Sport Fisheries in Michigan Waters (T/TS-7),1977-1978 (Box 14)
    - Early Assessment of Potential for Environmental Toxicity in the Great Lakes (T/TS-8) 1978-1981 (Box 14)
    - Release from PCB from sediment (T/TS-9) 1980 (Box 14)
    - Federal, State, Manufacturer, User and Environmental Group Interactions in Toxic Substance Regulation and Control (T/TS-10) 1978 (Box 14)
    - Contribution of Surface Micro-layer to Air/Water Exchange of Organic Pollutants (R/TS-12) 1979 (Box 14)
    - Review of PCB Research in the Great Lakes Area (R/TS-13) 1980 (Box 14)
    - The Role of Mysis Relicta in the Transport of PCB's through the Lake Michigan Ecosystem (T/TS-14) 1980-1982 (Box 14)
    - Effect of Wind and Waterflow on Volatilization of Pollutants from Natural Waters (R/TS-15) 1981-1982 (Box 14)
    - Development and refinement of Standard Methods for Wildlife Toxicology (R/TS-16) 1982, 3 folders (Box 14)
    - The Investigation of Ocular and Neural Lesions Observed in Rainbow Trout Following Exposure to Selected Organophosphate Esters (R/TS-19) 1982-1983 (Box 14)
    - Lysosomal Enzyme Release Assay as a Measure of Stress in Fish (R/TS-21) 1986 (Box 14)
    - Transfer Mechanism of PAHs in Great Lakes Zooplankton (R/TS-22) 1982-1984 (Box 14)
    - Studies on the Toxicological Significant of Toxaphene Residues in the Great Lakes Ecosystem (R/TS-24) 1983-1986 (Box 14)
    - Studies on the Composition and Photochemistry on the Polychlorinated Components of Toxaphene in the Great Lakes (R/TS-25) 1983-1985 (Box 14)
    - Toxaphene Compartition and Recycling in Lake Michigan (R/TS-26) 1983-1986 (Box 14)
    - Studies on the Toxicological Significance of Chlordane and Toxaphene Residues in Great Lakes Fish (R/TS-27) 1986-1988 (Box 14)
    - Phototoxicity of Polycyclic Aromatic Hydrocarbons to Lake Michigan Plankton (R/TS-28) 1985-1987 (Box 15)
    - The Effects of Dissolved Organic Matter on the Bioavailability of PAHs (R/TS-29) 1986-1987 (Box 15)
    - Effects of Maternal Exposure of Rainbow Trout to 2,3,7,8 Tetrachlorodibenzo-p-Dioxin (TCDD) on Reproduction (R/TS-31) 1988-1990 (Box 15)
  - Underwater Operations
    - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
    - Lee Somers Miscellaneous Research Projects (No ID number), scattered dates (Box 15)
    - Emergency Exit Tables (no ID number) (Box 15)
    - Underwater Technology Laboratory (E/DS-1) 1969 (Box 15)
    - Medical and Operating Standards for Working Divers (R/DS-3) 1977 (Box 15)
    - History of Decompression Devices (R/DS-6) 1988 (Box 15)
    - Analysis of Commercial and Recreational Diving Fatalities in MI 1965-1976 (R/UW-3), 1977 (Box 15)
    - Coldwater Drowning and in the Great Lakes or Inland Waters of Michigan (R/UW-4) 1977 (Box 15)
    - Accidental Submersion in Cold Water: A Study of Prognosis, Survivability and the Level of Hypothermia (R/UW-4) 1978 (Box 15)
    - The Effects of Hyperbaric Exposures on Menstruation, Fertilization, and Pregnancy (R/WS-2) 1979-1982 (Box 15)
    - Analysis of Multi-Level Diving Techniques and Practices (R/DS-6) 1987 (Box 15)
    - Marine Short Courses (A/FP-1) 1982 (Box 15)
    - Managing Dive Accidents in Michigan (A/FP-2) 1985 (Box 15)
    - A Diver's Guide to the U.S. Shore and Islands of Lake Superior (A/C-1) 1978-1980 (Box 15)
  - Water Quality and Quantity
    - Miscellaneous and subprogram information (Box 15)
    - Mathematical Modeling of Biological Production (MSG-1, R/EM-1) (Box 15)
    - Steady State Modeling Program (R-EMD-1) 1971-1973 (Box 15)
    - Biological Production (R/EMD-2) 1969-1971 (Box 15)
    - Dissolved Organic Phosphorus in Natural Water (R/EMD-2) 1971-1973 (Box 15)
    - Basin Morphometry, Sediments and Subsurface Geology (R/EMD-2) 1969-1972 (Box 15)
    - Hydrology (R/EMD-3) 1970-1973 (Box 15)
    - Shoreline Processes (R/EMD-4) 1970-1971 (Box 15)
    - Local Meteorology (R/EMD-7) 1970-1972 (Box 15)
    - Multi-Spectral Analysis of Shoreline Processes and Circulation Currents (R/EMD-9) 1970-1972 (Box 15)
    - Temperature Patterns in Grand Traverse Bay (R/EMD-9) 1970-1971 (Box 15)
    - Socioeconomic Forecasts for the Grand Traverse Bay Area (R/EMD-13) 1969-1970 (Box 15)
    - Evaluation of Future Technological Impacts (R/EMD-15) 1970-1973 (Box 15)
    - Environmental Impact of Cooling Towers (R/EMD-19) 1972-1975 (Box 15)
    - Social Science for Environmental Problems: Planning (R/EMD-16) 1970-1972 (Box 15)
    - Water Circulation (R/EMD-6) 1970-1971 (Box 15)
    - Water Quality Investigations (R/P-1) 1971-1973 (Box 15)
    - Waste Treatment Alternatives (R/P-2) 1970-1973 (Box 15)
    - Dynamics of Great Lakes Fisheries (R/ER-4) 1974 (Box 15)
    - Influence of Lake Michigan and Fox River Water on the Water Quality of Green Bay (R/ER-8) 1979-1980 (Box 15)
    - Whitefish Stocks in Northern Lake Michigan (R/ER-10) 1980-1981 (Box 15)
    - The Study of the Effect of a Rural Clean Water Project in the Saline Valley (R/ER-12) 1981-1984 (Box 15)
    - Reevaluation of the Plankton Diatoms of the Bass Island Region of Western Lake Erie (R/ER-13) 1987 (Box 16)
    - Documentation of the Effects of Water Quality in Changes in Western Lake Erie (R/ER-14) 1982-1983 (Box 16)
    - Characterization of Particulate Flux in Southeastern Lake Michigan (R/ER-16) 1983-1984 (Box 16)
    - Geochemical Pathfinders for Marine Placer Exploration (R/ER-17) 1985-1987 (Box 16)
    - Application of Diving Techniques to the Evaluation of Ferromanganese Resource (R/GO-1a) 1970-1972 (Box 16)
    - Prospects and Problems for Oil and Gas in the Environs of the Great Lakes (R/MR-1) 1977-1979 (1 folder, 2 binders) (Box 16)
    - Particulate Nitrogen And Carbon Study (R/EP-3) 1975-1976 (Box 16)
    - Petroleum Hydrocarbons and Heavy Metals in Great Lakes Surface Films (R/PSC-4) 1977-1979 (Box 16)
    - Education Program for the Lakewide Management Planning Process (A/FP-5) 1992 (Box 16)
  - Zebra Mussels
    - Approaches to Zebra Mussel Control through Intervention in Reproduction (R/ZM-1) 1991-1994 (Box 16)
    - Ship Operational and Safety Aspects of Ballast Water Exchange at Sea (R/ZM-2) 1991-1993 (Box 16)
    - Michigan Sea Grant Zebra Mussel Outreach Program (R/FP-4) 1992 (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous unidentified or non-numbered research material (Box 16)
- Research Materials
  The Research Materials series (.25 linear feet) consist of materials received in 2003 that is related to Sea Grant research but do not share the same organizational system as the Research Project Files. Of particular note is a collection of correspondence and publications based on Dr. Martin Nemiroff's research on "cold water drowning".
  - Closed Publications through 1987 (Box 21)
  - Cold Water Drowning
    - Correspondence, Articles, Publications, 7 folders (Box 21)
  - Diver Training Program 1975 (Box 21)
  - Hurricane Mitch Reconstruction 2002 (Box 21)
  - Hybrid Water Law R/RP-5 (Box 21)
  - Polluted Water Diving 1988 (Box 21)
  - Somers: P.R. and Workshop 1977-1978, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Sowers: Immune Response in Fish-eaters 1990 (Box 21)
- Audio and Visual Materials
  The Visual and Audio Materials series (2.25 linear feet) contains cassettes, photographs, slides, U-matic videos, VHS videos, and two 16mm films. The cassette series consists of a lecture on Fishing in Transition and The Sea Lamprey Story and cassettes that accompany the Indian Fishing Controversy, Michigan Sea Grant Introduction, and Zebra Mussels slide shows. There is a small series of photographs of various Great Lakes locations, as well as a Michigan Sea Grant-produced poster on the history and impact of aquatic nuisance species in the Great Lakes. A folder of promotional postcards that depict the life of the lakes, sand dunes, Sea Grant education, and the Grand Haven. The Sea Grant I folder contains the operation manual and original photographs of the vessel R/V Sea Grant I, purchased by the university in 1970. Along with the three slide shows, there are six slide binders that are organized by topic so that they could be easily be accessed for use in lectures. The U-matic, VHS, and 16mm films are productions created by the Michigan Sea Grant on topics related to or based on the Sea Grant's research.
  - Cassette Tapes
    - The Sea Lamprey Story, 2 audiocassettes (Box 16)
    - Great Lakes Fishing in Transition -- Bell Tone and Dukane Tone (Box 16)
  - Photographs
    - Lake Superior (Box 16)
    - Mackinac Bridge Authority (Box 16)
    - Grand Haven and Tawas City (Box 16)
    - Sea Grant College Status Ceremony 1981 (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified (Box 16)
    - Postcards: Promotional Items (Box 16)
    - Sea Grant I, Operation Manual and original Photographs (Box 16)
  - Poster and Timeline-Aquatic Nuisance Species (outsize) (Box 16)
  - Slides (with accompanying cassette tapes)
    - Indian Fishing Controversy (Box 16)
    - Introduction to Sea Grant (Box 16)
    - Zebra Mussels (Box 16)
    - Graphics/Displays/Personnel/Miscellaneous (Box 17)
    - Sea Lamprey (Box 17)
    - Indian Camps (Box 17)
    - Pollution (Box 17)
    - Transportation Shipping (Box 17)
    - Great Lakes Ecosystem and its Water Quality (Box 17)
  - Video Loaner Book (Box 18)
  - U-Matic Video Cassettes
    - The Fourth Sea Coast (Box 18)
    - The Great Lakes: No Free Lunch (Box 18)
    - The Great Lakes: Our Joint Heritage (Box 18)
    - Tolls on the Seaway (Box 18)
    - Toxics in the Great Lakes (Box 18)
    - Water Diversions (Box 18)
    - Winter Navigation on the Great Lakes (Box 18)
  - VHS Video cassettes
    - The Great Lakes Education Program (Box 18)
    - The Purple Loosestrife Project (Box 18)
    - Zebra Mussels Spawning (Box 18)
  - 16mm Film
    - Cold Water Drowning -- A Public Safety Message, 60 seconds (Box 18)
    - Cold Water Drowning -- A Public Safety Message, 6 minutes (Box 18)